NILSON MOLINA

5479 Greenboro Dr SE Kentwood, Michigan 49508 | (954)826-0073 | MolinaNilson@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am an Information Technology graduate who is eager and ready to join the work force. I am bilingual, speaking both English and Spanish, with a passion for all things tech related. Most of my technical experience comes from a multitude of small freelance work for several small businesses in the Miami, Florida area. Most recently, I created an ASP.NET multi-tiered web application hosted on Azure cloud services. The majority of my technical knowledge has been obtained by encountering a problem and finding a solution completely on my own, with the use of online trainings, books, and lots of Google. Because of this, I would consider my skills as Junior level, and would like an environment that could help me learn and grow professionally.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Software Development: C#, ASP.NET WebForms & MVC, Bootstrap, JQuery/Javascript, Azure Hosting

IT OS Experience: Windows XP/7/8/10/2003/2008R2, Mac OS X

EXPERIENCE

2014-2016 General Partner, NAMO Group Solutions, LLC

Pioneered creation of a new B2B startup, under parent company, specializing in software and IT solutions. Created a remote terminal server where customers could log in remotely to use software that we periodically updated and maintained. Created an invoicing web application utilizing Azure's stable web hosting service, and built upon ASP.NET framework (WebForms & MVC), while also adhering to the latest in responsive web design (Bootstrap).

2006-2014 Manager, NAMO Group Enterprise

Helped run all operational aspects of this family owned business of over 20 years. Creation of business website, software development, small network architect, accounting, customer support, inventory management, electronic hardware installation and repairs, etc...

2009-2012 Freelance Technician, Meco Parts / All World Heavy Equipment / Londo Motors / A-1 Venexport / Patriot Engineering / etc...

Updated software system every 6 months and performed several routine maintenance operations. Provided on-call IT support for some and sold several software offerings as an employee of NAMO Group Enterprise.

2004-2016 Miscellaneous Assignments

Over the years, I have repaired various electronics for friends, family, and clients gaining experience in diagnosing hardware and software failures, hardware replacement, virus prevention and removal, general OS maintenance, software training, etc...

EDUCATION

2009-2013 B.S. in Information Technology / Minor in Business Admin - Graduated Cum Laude Florida International University – Miami, FL